Allen H. May

1732 Pershing Boulevard Home: 937-902-2380 Dayton, Ohio 45420 email: allenhmay@gmail.com

CodePen: http://codepen.io/AllenMay/	Blog: http://allenmay.github.io/
Github: https://github.com/allenmay	Dribbble: https://dribbble.com/AllenHMay
LinkedIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/allenhmay	Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/allen.may.98
Twitter: https://twitter.com/AllenHMay	

IT Developer / Designer / Project Manager

Successful 20 year career in the information technology field. Lead Contributor/Project Manager for web development, internet integration, and software implementation projects. Ability to deliver solutions for internal operations, and external client needs. Demonstrated leadership by applying proven methods for success and sharing wisdom with the web development community. Current volunteer positions: Co-Organizer for Web Developers, and Co-Organizer for Southwest Ohio Givecamp. Career goal: to be part of a small team of industry leaders bringing solutions for client needs. Contribute to projects that craft unique and engaging web experiences that are technically solid and fulfill the practical need.

Developer Tools Experience:

Bootstrap | Bower | Command Line | CSS | EmberJS | Git | Github | Gulp | HTML | Javascript | Jekyll | Joomla | JQuery | Microsoft SQL | MVC Frameworks | MySQL | Patterns | Performance | Perl | PHP | Python | Ruby on Rails | SASS | SVG | Test Driven Development | WordPress | Yaml | Yeoman | Responsive Design | Sublime Text | Visual Studio Code | Coda

Historical Experience
 WordPress
• PHP
 Intranet Systems
 CRM (Customer Relationship Management)
 OnBase Workview / Case Management
• ASP.NET - C# /VB

Design Tools Experience:

Affinity Designer | Blender | Gimp | Google SketchUp | Hand Drawing | Illustrator | Inkscape | Photoshop

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Catapult Creative - Dayton, Ohio

Lead Developer

2017-Current

Define technology strategy for development pipeline. Evaluate and adjust tools, and key development procedures. Mentor
to and lead the web development team. Oversee technical design documentation process for correctness and timeliness.
Provide work estimates and input on the practicality of initial design goals. Provide custom PHP and Javascript solutions
where needed by projects.

OmniSpear - Miamisburg, Ohio

2015-2017

IT Services

Support CompuNet Clinical Laboratories (20hrs/week) in an IT resource role. My current employer has agreed to outsource
me back to my former employer to support my previous duties until they could backfill my position. I continue to work
20hrs/wk remote for CompuNet.

Web Developer

- Work on a variaty of web development projects for client needs.
 - O Laravel PHP framework development
 - o Frontend 'microsite' development
 - O WordPress administration and troubleshooting
 - o Client SEO optimization

Developer

• Manage and maintain company websites, develop custom internal applications, automate legacy data migrations and project manage company initiatives. Build custom business solutions using appropriate language, framework or systems. Technical project manager and application developer for the company OnBase ECM. Database administrator over MySQL and Microsoft SQL Server projects. Manage and develop reporting and business intelligence solutions for company and clients. Provide creative solutions to automate processes and deliver business data.

Billback Systems – Dayton, Ohio

2005 - 2008

Implementation Specialist

Primary technical contact for clients during project implementation of the Billback proprietary software. Install and customize software remotely and at client location. Project manage client expectations while working with their technical and finance departments to identify customization and features needed. Install foundation system of Apache/Java/MS-SQL, Billback application, edit XML and Java configuration files, troubleshooting system problems, hardware installation. Provided maintenance of corporate website and develop internal PHP Intranet tools.

Dayton Digital Networks – Dayton, Ohio

2003-2005 (Full-time)

Owner/Operator and Chief Technology Manager

2005-2007 (Part-time)

 Oversee all business and technical needs including equipment/hardware upgrades, operating system upgrades, configuration, and account provisioning. Managed client needs, negotiated contract agreements, managed marketing campaigns while continuing to engage local businesses for sales opportunities.

MCSi, Dayton, Ohio

2000-2003

Web Administrator

Responsible for both the public-facing corporate website and the extensive internal employee-only website. Used
Dreamweaver, text editors and the command line to write and manage custom HTML, CSS, PHP, Perl and XML code.
Administrator of Linux web server: Care and maintenance, troubleshooting, content management, and automate deployment
processes.

LexisNexis, Dayton, Ohio

1995-2000

Software Engineering

Processed LexisNexis proprietary data and formatted according to conversion projects' specifications. System engineering
projects include: automated testing systems, 'The Spectrum Tool', and smaller systems within Spectrum. Also involved in
troubleshooting UNIX, Mainframe, and Windows Operating Systems.

EDUCATION/TRAINING

- WorkView Implementation Hyland OnBase, May 2015 •
- Rails for Zombies 2 Code School, May 2015
- Rails for Zombies Redux Code School, April 2015
- **try-sql** Code School March, 2015

- Warming Up With Ember.js Code School, March 2015
- Writing Queries Using Microsoft SQL Server 2008 Transact-SQL Microsoft, May 2011
- What's New in Microsoft SQL Server 2008 for Database Development Microsoft, April 2010

A.A.S Electronics Engineering Technology, RETS Technical Center, 1991 C Programming using Turbo C++/UNIX Operating System – Sinclair Community College

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Co-Organizer - Dayton Web Developers

http://www.meetup.com/dayton-web-developers/

January 2015 - Current

Co-Organizer - Southwest Ohio Givecamp

http://southwestohiogivecamp.org/

March 2015 - Current

I help plan monthly meetings, recruit content specialists to speak at meetings and solicit sponsorship of the meetings.	I help manage the http://southwestohiogivecamp.org/website content and provide gather trending data through analytics.
Co-Organizer - CodePen Dayton http://www.meetup.com/CodePen-Dayton/ July 2015 - Current	Co-Organizer - Dayton PHP http://www.meetup.com/dayton-php/ March 2016 - Current
I help plan monthly meetings, recruit content specialists to speak at meetings and solicit sponsorship of the meetings.	I help plan monthly meetings, recruit content specialists to speak at meetings and solicit sponsorship of the meetings.